<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sam Harrison</title><link>https://samharrison.science/</link><description>Recent content on Sam Harrison</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samharrison.science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting more out of your Tado heating system with Python and the Tado API</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/tado-heating-python-api/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/tado-heating-python-api/</guid><description>We have recently installed a Tado thermostat to control our heating system. Tado is a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; heating system, in the sense that it is internet connected and lets you control your heating via its own app. The app is surprisingly good, but lacking in a few places, and so this got me wondering whether Tado had an API, and whether I could leverage this to get a bit more out of our heating system.</description></item><item><title>An honest review of going on holiday in an electric vehicle</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/ev-holidaying/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 08:19:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/ev-holidaying/</guid><description>There seems to be a concerted push amongst right-leaning media outlets recently to dial up the rhetoric around the downsides of electric vehicles. The same old, already-disproven arguments are being dragged to the surface for a last breath of air: they’re worse for the environment because of battery manufacturing and power generation (not true), they’re more likely to spontaneously catch fire (quite the opposite, and by a significant margin) and that inadequate charging infrastructure and low ranges make them a practical nightmare for anything but popping to the local supermarket.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Conda package for a project with Fortran and Python code</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/conda-package-fortran-python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/conda-package-fortran-python/</guid><description>Creating a Conda package is a great way to package and distribute your project’s software and its dependencies in a platform- and language-agnostic way. As Conda packages distribute compiled binaries, rather than your source code, they are not limited to specific programming languages (e.g. unlike Python packages distributed via PyPI). This makes them particularly suited to complex projects that might use a selection of different languages.
One common paradigm in scientific computing is the combined use of Fortran and Python.</description></item><item><title>Publications: DEPICTION</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/depiction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 15:51:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/depiction/</guid><description>Publications relating to the DEPICTION project.</description></item><item><title>Microplastics2022 conference wrap-up</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/microplastics2022-wrap-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/microplastics2022-wrap-up/</guid><description>Sitting on the TGV from Zurich to Paris, returning from an exciting and educational week spent at the Microplastics2022 conference in Monte Verità in Switzerland, I thought I should jot down some scattered thoughts on the conference. Things I learnt, themes I saw emerging, new science appearing and old science being adapted.
And then I thought these thoughts might just about be useful enough to others to warrant publishing, and so here is a brief post along those lines.</description></item><item><title>Create and hosting an interactive app with Jupyter, Voilà and Heroku</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/interactive-app-jupyter-voila-heroku/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 09:17:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/interactive-app-jupyter-voila-heroku/</guid><description>In this article, I will demonstrate how easy it is to create an interactive web app using Jupyter Notebooks, Voilà and Heroku. We will use Jupyter to create a simple notebook that plots a graph based on user input, turn this into an interactive dashboard using Voilà, and host it online using Heroku.
Before we get started, there are a few prerequisites:
I am presuming that you already have Jupyter installed and are familiar with using it and Python in general.</description></item><item><title>How to compare two empirical distributions</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/how-to-compare-two-distributions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/how-to-compare-two-distributions/</guid><description>The world is full of distributions - people&amp;rsquo;s height, incomes, exam results, average temperatures, heights of trees, sizes of microplastic particles in the environment. It stands to reason that there will be times when we need to compare these distributions to see how similar (or different) they are. For example, were summer temperatures similar this year to last year? Do two groups of people who buy different products make similar incomes?</description></item><item><title>Welcome! 👋</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 16:24:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Hey - welcome to my site! This is just a little post to say hello and because no blog would be complete without a &amp;ldquo;this is my first post&amp;rdquo; post.
In the future, this blog will be adorned with lots of useful tidbits about all things software, the environment, and environmental software. In the meantime, why not:
Check out my research Have a look at my publications Follow me on Twitter Have a nosey at some of my code on GitHub</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://samharrison.science/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:28:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/about/</guid><description>How this site was built This website was built using Hugo and lovingly adapted from the Coder theme. On top of these, I use nb2hugo to convert Jupyter Notebooks to a Markdown format supported by Hugo. I use Jupyter Notebooks to write blog articles that contain a lot of code, to make sure bugs are kept to a minimum (because I can test the code prior to converting to Markdown).</description></item><item><title>Publications: ETERNAL</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/eternal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/eternal/</guid><description>Publications relating to the ETERNAL project.</description></item><item><title>Publications: FRAGMENT-MNP</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/fragment-mnp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/fragment-mnp/</guid><description>Publications relating to the FRAGMENT-MNP project and model.</description></item><item><title>Publications: NanoFASE</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanofase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanofase/</guid><description>Publications relating to the NanoFASE project and model.</description></item><item><title>Publications: NanoSolveIT</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanosolveit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanosolveit/</guid><description>Publications relating to the NanoSolveIT project.</description></item><item><title>Publications: SAbyNA and ASINA</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/sabyna_asina/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/sabyna_asina/</guid><description>Publications relating to the SAbyNA and ASINA projects.</description></item><item><title>Publications: UKSCAPE SPEED</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/speed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/speed/</guid><description>Publications relating to the UK-SCAPE SPEED project.</description></item><item><title>My Projects</title><link>https://samharrison.science/projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 17:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/projects/</guid><description>Projects that I am currently or have previously been involved in.
EMIFACT-MNP January 2023 to December 2024 The goal of EMIFACT-MNP is to develop a model of Micro and Nanoplastic EMIssion FACTors in Europe. Quantifying emissions of plastics to the environment is crucial to be able to make accurate fate and exposure predictions. In this project, we are using probabilistic material flow analysis approaches alongside knowledge on microplastic degradation and fragmentation, to be able to predict size-distributed emissions of a broad range of polymers across their whole lifecycle.</description></item><item><title>My Research</title><link>https://samharrison.science/my-research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 17:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/my-research/</guid><description>Hi 👋, I&amp;rsquo;m Sam - an environmental modeller and self-proclaimed research software engineer at the UK Centre for Ecology &amp;amp; Hydrology, Lancaster, with a background in quantum physics and software development. My main specialism is in the development of geospatial fate and exposure models of potential pollutants in soils and surface waters, including micro- and nanoplastics, nanomaterials and metals. Through this, I am interested in integrating models to better quantify the impact of environmental change, giving us a deeper understanding of human-environment interactions.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://samharrison.science/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/contact/</guid><description>Got a question, an idea, a comment or just want to chat? I&amp;rsquo;m always happy to hear from new folk, so drop me an email or ping me a message on Twitter.
sharrison@ceh.ac.uk @samharrison7 +44 (0)1524 595882 UK Centre for Ecology &amp;amp; Hydrology, Lancaster Environment Centre, Lancaster University, LA1 4AP</description></item></channel></rss>