<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sam Harrison</title><link>https://samharrison.science/</link><description>Recent content on Sam Harrison</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 16:24:40 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samharrison.science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome! 👋</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 16:24:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Hey - welcome to my site! This is just a little post to say hello and because no blog would be complete without a &amp;ldquo;this is my first post&amp;rdquo; post.
In the future, this blog will be adorned with lots of useful tidbits about all things software, the environment, and environmental software. In the meantime, why not:
Check out my research Have a look at my publications Follow me on Twitter Have a nosey at some of my code on GitHub</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://samharrison.science/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:28:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/about/</guid><description>How this site was built This website was built using Hugo and lovingly adapted from the Coder theme. On top of these, I use nb2hugo to convert Jupyter Notebooks to a Markdown format supported by Hugo. I use Jupyter Notebooks to write blog articles that contain a lot of code, to make sure bugs are kept to a minimum (because I can test the code prior to converting to Markdown).</description></item><item><title>Publications: ETERNAL</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/eternal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/eternal/</guid><description>Publications relating to the ETERNAL project.</description></item><item><title>Publications: FRAGMENT-MNP</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/fragment-mnp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/fragment-mnp/</guid><description>Publications relating to the FRAGMENT-MNP project and model.</description></item><item><title>Publications: NanoFASE</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanofase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanofase/</guid><description>Publications relating to the NanoFASE project and model.</description></item><item><title>Publications: NanoSolveIT</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanosolveit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/nanosolveit/</guid><description>Publications relating to the NanoSolveIT project.</description></item><item><title>Publications: SAbyNA and ASINA</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/sabyna_asina/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/sabyna_asina/</guid><description>Publications relating to the SAbyNA and ASINA projects.</description></item><item><title>Publications: UKSCAPE SPEED</title><link>https://samharrison.science/publications/speed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/publications/speed/</guid><description>Publications relating to the UK-SCAPE SPEED project.</description></item><item><title>My Projects</title><link>https://samharrison.science/projects/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 17:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/projects/</guid><description>Projects that I am currently or have previously been involved in.
ETERNAL September 2022 to August 2026 The aim of this EU Horizon Europe project is to reduce the environmental impact of pharmaceutical products throughout their life cycle. Our work is to assessing the environmental risk posed by commonly used pharmaceuticals, including how product and process modifications investigated in the project will reduce this risk.
FRAGMENT-MNP October 2021 to September 2023 I am currently leading this project, funded by the European Chemical Industry Council’s Long-Range Research Initiative (Cefic-LRI), to develop a mechanistic model of micro- and nanoplastic fragmentation in the environment.</description></item><item><title>My Research</title><link>https://samharrison.science/my-research/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 17:58:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/my-research/</guid><description>Hi 👋, I&amp;rsquo;m Sam - an environmental modeller and self-proclaimed research software engineer at the UK Centre for Ecology &amp;amp; Hydrology, Lancaster, with a background in quantum physics and software development. My main specialism is in the development of geospatial fate and exposure models of potential pollutants in soils and surface waters, including micro- and nanoplastics, nanomaterials and metals. Through this, I am interested in integrating models to better quantify the impact of environmental change, giving us a deeper understanding of human-environment interactions.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://samharrison.science/contact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/contact/</guid><description>Got a question, an idea, a comment or just want to chat? I&amp;rsquo;m always happy to hear from new folk, so drop me an email or ping me a message on Twitter.
sharrison@ceh.ac.uk @samharrison7 +44 (0)1524 595882 UK Centre for Ecology &amp;amp; Hydrology, Lancaster Environment Centre, Lancaster University, LA1 4AP</description></item></channel></rss>