<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sam Harrison</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sam Harrison</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 16:02:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samharrison.science/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a Conda package for a project with Fortran and Python code</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/conda-package-fortran-python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 16:02:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/conda-package-fortran-python/</guid><description>Creating a Conda package is a great way to package and distribute your project’s software and its dependencies in a platform- and language-agnostic way. As Conda packages distribute compiled binaries, rather than your source code, they are not limited to specific programming languages (e.g. unlike Python packages distributed via PyPI). This makes them particularly suited to complex projects that might use a selection of different languages.
One common paradigm in scientific computing is the combined use of Fortran and Python.</description></item><item><title>Microplastics2022 conference wrap-up</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/microplastics2022-wrap-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/microplastics2022-wrap-up/</guid><description>Sitting on the TGV from Zurich to Paris, returning from an exciting and educational week spent at the Microplastics2022 conference in Monte Verità in Switzerland, I thought I should jot down some scattered thoughts on the conference. Things I learnt, themes I saw emerging, new science appearing and old science being adapted.
And then I thought these thoughts might just about be useful enough to others to warrant publishing, and so here is a brief post along those lines.</description></item><item><title>Create and hosting an interactive app with Jupyter, Voilà and Heroku</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/interactive-app-jupyter-voila-heroku/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 09:17:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/interactive-app-jupyter-voila-heroku/</guid><description>In this article, I will demonstrate how easy it is to create an interactive web app using Jupyter Notebooks, Voilà and Heroku. We will use Jupyter to create a simple notebook that plots a graph based on user input, turn this into an interactive dashboard using Voilà, and host it online using Heroku.
Before we get started, there are a few prerequisites:
I am presuming that you already have Jupyter installed and are familiar with using it and Python in general.</description></item><item><title>How to compare two empirical distributions</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/how-to-compare-two-distributions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/how-to-compare-two-distributions/</guid><description>The world is full of distributions - people&amp;rsquo;s height, incomes, exam results, average temperatures, heights of trees, sizes of microplastic particles in the environment. It stands to reason that there will be times when we need to compare these distributions to see how similar (or different) they are. For example, were summer temperatures similar this year to last year? Do two groups of people who buy different products make similar incomes?</description></item><item><title>Welcome! 👋</title><link>https://samharrison.science/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 16:24:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://samharrison.science/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Hey - welcome to my site! This is just a little post to say hello and because no blog would be complete without a &amp;ldquo;this is my first post&amp;rdquo; post.
In the future, this blog will be adorned with lots of useful tidbits about all things software, the environment, and environmental software. In the meantime, why not:
Check out my research Have a look at my publications Follow me on Twitter Have a nosey at some of my code on GitHub</description></item></channel></rss>